Girls Will Be Girls is a drama, romance film directed by Shuchi Talati.
In a strict boarding school nestled in the Himalayas,
16-year-old Mira discovers desire and romance.
But her sexual, rebellious awakening is disrupted by her
mother who never got to come of age herself.
Mira, played by Preeti Panigrahi.
Anila, played by Kani Kusruti.
Sri, played by Kesav Binoy Kiron.
Priya, played by Kajol Chugh.
Divya, played by Nandini Verma.
Mrs. Bansal, played by Devika Shahani.
Girls Will Be Girls is a 2024 coming-of-age drama film,
written and directed by Shuchi Talati.
It stars Preeti Panigrahi, Kani Kusruti, and Kesav Binoy Kiron.
An Indian and French co-production, the film is Talati's feature directorial
debut, as well as the acting debut of both Panigrahi and Kiron.
The film is set in a boarding school in the Himalayan foothills, and centers around teenager Mira's romance with a charming
new student, her subsequent sexual awakening, and at times strained relationship with her protective mother.
The film premiered at the 2024 Sundance Film Festival, where
it participated in the competition section.
It was released on 18 December 2024, on Amazon Prime Video.
Among the film's accolades, it won the Independent Spirit John Cassavetes Award.
The film explores themes of coming of age, woman director, female writer.
The tone is emotional.